This way, please.
世子请
Kneel down.
还不快跪
All of my family
老奴全家都在此处
are privileged to see Your Highness.
给世子请安
Everyone, get up.
大家快起来
You especially don't need to kneel to me.
尤其是您可不能跪
Please get up.
大家请起
Get up.
起来吧
Why did you say
世子为什么说
I don't need to kneel to you?
老奴不能跪呢
Because according to military regulations,
因为我北椋军中有军礼
you don't have to kneel.
无需跪拜
But I retired from the army long ago.
可老奴早就离开军伍了
Once you were a soldier,
一日北椋军
you'll always be a soldier.
一生北椋军
You've never left the army.
您始终未曾离开
Wang Linquan, foot soldier of Hupu Battalion,
北椋虎扑营马前卒
is honored to see Your Highness.
王林泉参见世子
Xu Fengnian, junior of North Liang Army,
北椋后辈徐凤年
is honored to see you.
见过老兵
Under your leadership,
北椋有世子在
North Liang will have a bright future.
未来可期啊
Your old servant
老奴便是死
can die in peace.
也瞑目了
Don't call yourself servant.
别用这个奴字
You're an elder to me.
您是我长辈
All right.
好
Chudong,
初冬
come here.
过来
This is my daughter,
这是王某的女儿
Chudong.
名为初冬
(Wang Linquan's youngest daughter Wang Chudong) If you don't mind,
世子要是不嫌弃
let her wait upon you tonight.
今夜就让小女侍寝吧
- Ah?
啊
Father.
父王
Where are your manners?
怎么不叫人呢
Aunt.
姨娘
It's wrong.
叫错了
Mother.
娘亲
You're in such a hurry.
跑得这么急
What happened?
出什么事了
North Liang is our old enemy.
北椋为我青州宿敌
You shouldn't humiliate yourself
不管是民间还是官面
in front of the enemy.
父王都不该如此折辱自己
What nonsense are you talking about?
乱七八糟 说些什么
You asked Wang Linquan to welcome Xu Fengnian.
您让王林泉去接徐凤年
You must've considered it thoroughly.
这定是有您的谋策
But you shouldn't have let him keel to Xu.
但也不应该让他下跪吧
Xu Xiao.
徐骁
What a master of intrigue.
下得一手好棋啊
Does Wang work for Xu Xiao?
王林泉是徐骁的人
Come back.
回来
Where are you going?
去哪儿
I'm going to kill the whole family of Wang.
我去灭了王家全族
Wang has been working for me
王林泉在我身边
under a false identity for years.
躲了这么多年
Why did he create such a big scene
为何今日大张旗鼓
to meet Xu Fengnian today?
去见徐凤年
What's his purpose
他现在暴露身份
of exposing his identity now?
对他有什么好处
It's...
这
It's a bargain.
这是交换
Bargain?
交换
Xu Xiao asked Wang to expose his identity
徐骁让王林泉亮出身份
in order to show me
就是要告诉我
he's voluntarily removed his spay
他主动撤去暗棋
in exchange for my guarantee.
要换我一个态度
Guarantee of what?
什么态度
Xu Fengnian's hereditary dignity
徐凤年
held in perpetuity.
世袭罔替
He wants me to guarantee that I won't make difficulties.
要换我不要从中阻挠
He's humiliating you.
他分明就是折辱
Xu Fengnian happens to be in Qingzhou.
反正人在青州
Shall we kill the Wang family
不如把王家带着徐凤年
and Xu together?
一块灭了
Don't be anxious.
不必焦躁
Let's wait for Wang's visit.
且等王林泉登门吧
How could he come to court death?
王林泉怎么会登门送死
He must've run away with Xu Fengnian.
肯定跟徐凤年跑了
You can go now.
下去吧
Did Wu Liuding say
吴六鼎是说
we can take action tomorrow?
明日可动手
Yes.
没错
I'll lead the navy out of camp tomorrow
明日我再率水军出营
to intercept and kill Xu Fengnian.
截杀徐凤年
Let him assist us.
让他随行协助
Who is it?
谁啊
Me.
我
Your Highness.
世子
Let me introduce to you.
给你引荐一下
This is Mr. Wang Linquan.
这位是王林泉王老先生
Aren't you Mr. Lin, the Third Graduate in the Palace Examination?
这不是林家那个探花吗
Lord of Jing'an is determined to
靖安王对林家只有一个态度
exterminate your entire family,
那就是屠尽满门
leaving no chance for your revival.
斩草除根
I'm in charge of it.
这老夫就负责此事
But General
可大将军
gave your family a chance to live.
还是给了林家一线生机
Your mother
你娘
is right in my residence.
就在我府上
My mother...
我娘
Is my mother here?
我娘在这儿
Come.
走
I'll take you to see her.
我带你见一面
Your mother is in there.
你娘就在里面
Who is it?
谁呀
Mother.
娘
It was all my fault that
林家陷入如此境地
our family got into such a situation.
全是儿子的错
I can't atone for my sin even I die a hundred times.
儿子百死莫赎
North Liang is a dangerous place.
北椋如虎狼之地
How did you escape
你刺杀失败
after the failed assassination?
怎么逃出来的呀
Tell me.
说呀
I've taken refuge
儿子现如今
under North Liang.
已投靠北椋门下
Mother.
娘
How many members of our family
现如今
are there left alive?
林家还剩下多少人活着
I come back this time
儿子此次回来
to send all of you
是想把大家
to North Liang.
一起送到北椋去
Rest assured.
您放心
I will avenge myself on it.
这个仇我一定会报
Come here.
你过来
As a
我林家
scholar-gentry family,
书香门第
we cherish ethics, rites and law the most.
最讲礼教法度
Xu Xiao is actually a traitor.
那徐骁实为国贼
Everyone has the right to kill him.
人人得而诛之
I was proud that
你去刺杀徐凤年
you went to assassinate Xu Fengnian.
为娘我很是骄傲
Nobody would blame you even if
就是林家从此灭门
our entire family was exterminated.
也没人怪罪你啊
I didn't expect you to be a coward.
你竟然胆小畏死
I'd rather you die
宁愿你死了
than you live in infamy!
我也不想你这样活下去
Mother.
娘
You've turned to North Liang now.
你已是北椋门生
Don't call me mother again.
这声娘我受不起
You're
我当是
dead to me.
我儿子已经死了
The Lin Family will stay in Qingzhou.
林家人自会留在青州
No one will follow you to North Liang.
绝不会有人跟你到北椋
Get out.
你走吧
I can send your family out of Qingzhou,
我可以把林家的人送出青州
but I have two conditions.
但是我有两个条件
Shoot.
你说
First,
第一个
the Lin family has been stationed in Qingzhou for years
林家驻扎青州多年
with deep foundation.
根基深厚
Even though they were exterminated,
就算是灭门
there are still old subordinates of theirs.
也依然有不少旧部留存
I want you to take a ship to town tomorrow
我要你明日乘船进城
and contact the old subordinates.
联系林家旧部
What for?
为什么这么做
The Lin Family has been fighting against Lord of Jing'an for years.
林家跟靖安王这斗了这么多年
They must know
靖安王许多秘密还有把柄
many of his dirty secrets.
只有林家知道
OK.
好
I'll find out all his secrets
我会把所有的秘密全都问出来
and tell you.
然后告诉你
Don't tell me.
也不是告诉我
Tell His Highness.
告诉世子
What's the other condition?
那第二个条件是什么
From now on,
从此以后
you must live only for the safety of His Highness.
你只为世子的安危而活
If he sustains any minor injury
世子在青州境内
in Qingzhou,
但凡有一点点伤
I'll turn your family over to Lord of Jing'an.
我都会把林家的人交给靖安王
Do you understand?
你懂了吗
Uncle Wang.
王伯
Your Highness.
世子
It's General's idea.
这是大将军的意思
Let me take care of it.
您让我处理吧
I'll die fighting for His Highness.
我会为世子而战死
Till then,
在我死之前
I'll never let him get hurt or put him in danger.
我绝对不会让世子受伤遇险
Good.
很好
Keep that in mind.
记住你说的话
Well,
这个
about my daughter...
侍寝的事
I was
今天
graceless.
是我唐突了
Never mind.
不打紧 不打紧
You're an elder to me.
您是北椋前辈
How can I do that
我做那种事
to your daughter?
我还算人吗
But I'm willing to devote her to you.
这是我愿意的啊
But she is not.
您女儿可不愿意啊
That's right.
这倒是
Right.
是
I'll persuade her.
我劝劝她
I'll accompany you to town tomorrow.
明天我陪你进城
Hopefully Xu Fengnian leaves the island today.
希望徐凤年今日可以离岛
If he doesn't,
徐凤年若不离岛
we'll go all the way to the island.
我们就杀上姥山
How mighty you are!
世子威武
Please take care of yourself.
世子一路保重啊
This way.
请
I'll leave Fengzi Battalion to you.
那凤字营就劳烦王伯照顾了
Lord of Jing'an has been living in Xiangfan for long.
这靖安王久居欀樊
Once you go to town,
一旦进城
your life is in his hands.
生死可就交在他手里了
Don't worry.
王伯放心
Even if he wants to kill me,
赵衡就算真要杀我
he won't do it in town.
也不会在城里
Why don't you take Fengzi Battalion with you?
要不把凤字营带上
Without transfer orders from the Ministry of War
兵部无调令
and the imperial edict,
皇帝未下旨
the army of North Liang can't enter Xiangfan.
北椋军不能进欀樊城
Xu Xiao is on his way to the capital.
徐骁进京路上
Don't give our enemy any excuse.
别落下话柄
Sounds reasonable.
也有道理
We have to leave now.
那我们就先告辞了
Wait for a minute.
稍等稍等
Wait for what?
等什么
She'll come soon.
马上就来
In a minute.
马上
Father, do you want to see me?
爹 你叫我啊
You need a person
世子此去
who is familiar with Xiangfan during the trip.
总要有一个熟悉欀樊的人跟着
Let Chudong go with you.
就让小女初冬跟在世子身边
At night,
晚上嘛
you may have a chat and get acquainted with each other.
你们多聊聊熟悉熟悉
I won't go.
我不去
Don't be childish.
别胡闹
Isn't it enough that
咱们王家为北椋
our family take such a big risk for North Liang?
冒这么大风险还不够
Why must you devote me to him?
还得把我也献出去
What's so great about him?
世子有什么了不起的
He was just born in a powerful family.
不过是生来命好
You're ridiculous!
你放肆
I'm ashamed.
让世子见笑了
Uncle Wang.
王伯
I'm going to town by myself.
我一个人进城
Don't bother your daughter.
就不劳烦令千金了
Well...
这
She has been spoiled since childhood.
这小女从小娇生惯养
Please forgive her
失了礼数
for being impolite.
世子莫怪啊
Don't mention it.
王伯客气
Please stay.
您留步
We'll see you soon.
我们走了
Take care.
慢走
The girl talked nonsense just now.
刚才那丫头乱说话
Your Highness,
世子
don't be angry.
不必动气
How could I be angry with her?
我怎么会生她的气呢
Grandpa Wei,
魏爷爷
I feel uncomfortable
我心里觉得不舒服
because I probably know
是因为我大概想到
Xu Xiao's plans in Qingzhou.
徐骁在青州的布局了
Xu Xiao has a similar style to my master.
徐骁行事和我师父一样
His plans are usually interlinked.
都是连环行棋
Since Uncle Wang is exposed,
如今王伯暴露
I think his next move
下一步棋
has been quite ready.
也就准备好了
I've figured it out since Wang Linquan proposed to
从王林泉让他女儿侍寝开始
let his daughter sleep with me.
我大概就明白了
Let's talk about it after we get into town.
进城再说吧
Hopefully I worried too much.
但愿是我多想了
Didn't I give you orders
我不是下令了吗
and ask you to stay on the island?
凤字营留在岛上
We're all dressed as scholars.
就我们三个书生打扮
Everything will be fine.
万无一失的
Will a scholar take this?
你家书生带这个
Put it away.
收起来
What about the two little fellas?
那俩小家伙呢
They stayed on the island
它们和鱼幼薇在一起
with Yu Youwei.
留在了岛上
She has a cat.
那丫头养猫
She may take care of them.
也能照顾那幼兽
Go away.
走开
Don't come.
别过来啊
Stay away.
别过来 别过来
Your Highness.
世子
There are ships.
有船
What a coincidence.
这么巧就遇上了
It seems God wants him to die.
看来也是天要亡他
Father. Come here.
爹 就是这儿
Look.
快看
The navy of Qingzhou.
青州水师
If you saw it,
你既然看见了
why didn't you take me to the dock?
怎么不拉我去码头
It's too late.
赶不上了
It's too late when you get to the dock
从这下码头再出船
and take a boat.
怎么也赶不上了
I...
我啊
I should have gone with His Highness.
我就该陪着世子一块儿去
He's about to run into them.
要遇上了
Zhao Heng and his son are not fools.
那靖安王父子不是蠢货
If they kill His Highness,
真要害了世子
the army of North Liang will storm into Qingzhou.
那北椋必定杀至青州
We mustn't miss the chance today.
今日不能再错失机会
After he's dead,
到时候
we'll send his body to North Liang.
给他捞个全尸送回北椋
It's good enough.
也算是仁至义尽了
Don't mind his father.
别管剑冢那家伙了
When he arrives,
等他赶到
Xu Fengnian will be dead already.
徐凤年早死了
Don't move the flagship.
旗舰不动
The left and right ships,
左右两舰
sink the enemies' ship.
击沉敌船
None of them shall survive!
不留活口
They are coming to us.
是冲咱们来的
Halt!
停船
Take in sail.
收帆
What's the pole used for?
那大杆子是干吗的
It's patting pole,
那是拍杆
used to smash ship.
砸船用的
It's tremendously heavy.
拍杆重量惊人
With two pats,
这两下砸下去
the ship will sink.
怕是船都没了
Your Highness.
世子
Can we use our weapons?
可以用兵刃吗
Sure.
准了
Here.
来
Break off!
给我断开
Fengqi.
凤起
What a valiant general.
真是勇将
He's great.
好厉害
Get ready!
准备
Thanks.
谢谢
Thank His Highness.
你谢世子吧
He asked me to protect you.
他让我护着你
Ning Emei.
宁峨眉
Yes.
在
Seize the ship.
夺船
Wow.
哎呀
What a bold strategy!
好一个近战夺船
Grandpa Wei,
魏爷爷
can you go aboard the ship?
能上那艘船吗
A piece of cake.
小事一桩
Is he going to pull the ship by hand?
这是要靠人力把船拉过去吗
Sir, please help us.
请前辈出手
They are just small fry
什么小鱼小虾
unworthy of being my opponent.
也配让我出手
Does he have supernatural power?
这人莫非天生神力
It looks like Chixia Swordplay.
好像是赤霞剑诀
Enough.
可以了
It's said that North Liang have many masters.
都说北椋高手众多
As we can see,
今日一见
they deserve the reputation.
名不虚传呀
Get my Immortal Arm Bow.
取我神臂弓来
Yes.
是
It's all right.
已经没事了
Your family have been sent away one by one.
林家的人已经陆续送走
Uncle Wang saved many people.
王伯救下不少人
He didn't knock walnut in vain.
核桃倒是没白敲啊
He's almost mastered Dahuangting.
大黄庭也差不多是他自己的了
They finally come.
终于到了
Yet they don't move.
来了也不动
I'm afraid they're frightened to death.
怕是吓破了胆
The so-called Sword Tomb of the Wu family is just so-so.
吴家剑冢不过如此
Witnessing the fight,
那艘小船见到厮杀
why doesn't the boat leave?
为什么还不走
What does he want?
他想干什么
Who is this?
这又是谁
Is that Xu Fengnian?
是徐凤年吗
Who is it?
哪位
Sword Tomb.
剑冢
Wu Liuding.
吴六鼎
Your mother
你娘
fled from her family
当年反出吴家
and damaged its reputation.
剑冢声名受损
Someone must
这屈辱
pay for that.
总要还上
Mother's debt should be paid by her son.
母债子偿
I will bear
我娘的祸事
my mother's misfortune.
我接着
If you have the guts,
吴家若有胆气
go to North Liang to collect your debts.
大可以来北椋讨债
If you say so,
你要接
I won't stop you.
便接着吧
What is he doing?
这是做什么
Is Sword Tomb of the Wu family actually so powerful?
吴家剑冢竟然如此之强
Don't you dare annoy me!
别往我脑袋上扔船
Who're you?
前辈是哪一位
None of your business.
关你球事
Your Highness!
世子
He can use his genuine spirit skillfully.
真气用得倒是熟了
Who is the old man?
那老头又是何方神圣
Catch.
接着
Retreat!
收兵
Fujiang Armor.
伏将红甲
Take care.
小心
Throw halberds.
扔戟
Where did the armor come from?
那红甲人又是哪儿冒出来的
Who are the people
那艘旗舰上
on the flagship
到底是谁
trying to assassinate Xu Fengnian?
想对徐凤年下手
No matter who they are,
那不管是谁
they've made a big mistake.
都闯下大祸了
Attacking the son of Lord of North Liang
对北椋世子行凶
is a crime that can be directly reported to the emperor.
打御状都够
His ship comes over.
徐凤年的船靠过来了
He's well protected by those freaks.
身边都是怪物
It's hard to kill him.
看来是杀不成了
Bring him up.
把人带上来
Yes.
是
You're not with the government.
你无官身
You'd better leave.
就别在船上了
I'm getting off, then.
我先下船
I'll call on you when I get back to town.
回城之后登门拜会
Son of Lord of Jing'an invites Son of Lord of North Liang to board.
靖安王世子有请北椋世子上船
I've long heard of your name.
久闻北椋徐凤年大名
Today I have the honor to meet you.
今日得见
You're true to your name.
名不虚传
Son of Lord of Jing'an.
靖安王世子
That's me.
正是赵某
Did you try to kill me?
这是要杀我
It's a shame.
惭愧啊
I was on a drill with the navy,
赵某随水师演练
not expecting a villain took over power.
却被宵小之徒夺权
The villain dared to
贼人大胆
assassinate Mr. Xu.
竟然还想刺杀徐兄
Fortunately, you're not hurt.
幸好徐兄无事啊
I'm so relieved.
赵某才松了口气
Didn't you say he took over power?
不是夺权吗
Why is he tied up?
怎么还把人绑上了
During the chaos,
方才大乱之势
I took the opportunity
我借机出手
to overpower him.
将这贼子擒住了
Except for seizing the ship,
贼子夺船不算
he tried to assassinate you.
竟然还想刺杀徐兄
He is so vicious.
当真可恨
Who is he?
他是谁
The son of Wei Dong,
水军都统
and the commander of navy,
韦栋之子
Wei Wei.
韦玮
Was him the one who shot arrows?
射箭的也是他
Yes, it was him.
就是此人
Does he know
那他知不知道
it's a capital crime?
这可是死罪
You're right.
徐兄说的是
Assassinating the son of Lord of North Liang
刺杀北椋世子
is surely a capital crime.
只能是死罪了
Let me
赵某不才
seek justice
为徐兄
for you.
讨个公道
Mr. Xu,
徐兄
have you cooled down?
消气没有
You're fast.
杀得够快的
To eliminate traitors for the country
为国除奸
is of great urgency.
刻不容缓
You're fully prepared, aren't you?
你这是早就备好了
I don't know what you're talking about.
赵某听不懂徐兄在说什么
Don't you have any responsibilities at all?
你就一点责任都没有
After all, it was my man who did this.
毕竟是我属下夺权
Though I'm innocent,
我虽无辜
I must be blamed for not disciplining them well.
可也算御下无方
Please forgive me, Mr. Xu.
还请徐兄体谅
Would you have a drink with me
要不这样
so I can make an apology?
我请徐兄吃酒谢罪
There's blood on your nose.
沾到血了
Thanks.
多谢
What do you want?
什么意思
Don't waste your money on inviting me to drink.
吃酒就不必了 多破费啊
I'll take that as your apology.
这就算是谢罪了
Xu Fengnian!
徐凤年
Why don't you call me Mr. Xu?
不叫徐兄了
As long as it cools you down.
徐兄消气就好
You're broad-minded.
雅量高致
Lord of Jing'an has a good son.
靖安王养了个好儿子
I'm impressed.
佩服
They are all right.
没事了
Xu Fengnian has many masters work for him.
这徐凤年手下高手还挺多
How can you call his name directly?
怎能直呼世子姓名
He has a lecherous and lustful reputation.
这徐凤年素有纨绔好色的名声
I didn't expect him to be worse than in the rumors.
没想到比传闻更加恶劣
On arriving at the island,
这才上岛
he wants to take me away.
就想让我跟他走
I won't listen to
这样的世子
such a playboy.
我可不会听他的
It has nothing to do
这件事啊
with His Highness.
与世子无关
I proposed it.
是我的意思
When he leaves Xiangfan,
等世子离开欀樊时
you should go with him.
你跟着走吧
You just met him,
这才见一面
yet you want to devote your daughter to him.
你就要把自己的女儿送出去
Why?
为什么
It's for your own good.
爹是为你好
The assassin who ambushed from underwater
刚才水下偷袭的
was Fujiang Armor again.
又是伏将红甲
It seems that those who want to kill me
看来想杀我的人
have followed me to Qingzhou.
一路跟到了青州
Whose instigation was he under?
会是谁指使伏将红甲
Was it Zhao Xun?
难道是刚才的赵珣
If it was him,
如果是赵珣指使的话
Fujiang Armor would
红甲偷袭会和楼船强攻
cooperate better with him.
配合得更好才是
The one who tried to kill me
背后要杀我的这个人
was using Zhao Xun.
是在借赵珣的势
Unfortunately...
可惜
Unfortunately, we don't know who it is.
可惜不知道是谁
We'll meet again.
会再见的